Finding Aid for the Mozelle Adams Core Collection
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Mozelle Adams Core Collection
1942-1946
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0728
.42 linear feet
Biographical Note:
Mozelle Adams Core was a student at Vanderbilt University in the 1940’s. During her Vanderbilt career, she was a student of Professor Donald Davidson. Davidson taught English at Vanderbilt University through his entire professional career (1920-1968). He was also a poet, novelist, and critic. Davidson was a key figure at Vanderbilt during his time, and he played a role in The Fugitive and Agrarian groups which were centered at the university in the 1920s and 1930s.
Mozelle Adams Core donated this collection pertaining to Donald Davidson on January 25, 2010.
Scope and Content:
This .21 linear foot collection consists mostly of papers written by Mozelle Adams Core while she was a student of Donald Davidson. The papers include reports, analysis of major works as well as many short stories. Some papers are typed while others are hand written. Many of these papers also include handwritten comments from Donald Davidson. Also, this collection includes a letter written by Davidson to the Vanderbilt University Press urging them to consider publishing students which he regards as the future writers and publishers of the country. Finally, the collection includes a transcript of an oral story of Dorothy Boykin.
- “Mr. Bill Hoskitt is Dead,”, March 5, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- “Study of Mam’me Etienne and Max, Ward Allison Dorrance,”, November 27, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- “Pretty Flowers,” n. d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
- “Study of How Beautiful with Shoes,”, February 27, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- “Exercise taken from Brooks and Warren, Analysis of Winter Remembered, by John Crowe Ransom,”, March 15. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- “Henchard, Mayor of Casterbridge,”, November 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- “Reports: Brave New World, Victory, Tess of the D’ Urbervilles, Madame Bovary,”, December 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- “The Relation of the Chorus in the Suppliants to the Play as a Whole,”, December, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- “Browning’s New Method,”, May 9, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- “The Captive and its Source,”, February 23, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Unidentified, Incomplete Short Story, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- “Hat,”, May 20, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- “Daughters of Job,”, January 22, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- “Funeral,”, December 11, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- “A Firer of Furnaces,”, November 16, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- “Patterns in Mrs. Dalloway,”, December 13, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- “Yea Yea and Nay Nay,” n. d. (Box 1, Folder 17)
- “Dark Fried Tobacco From Seed to Market,”, October 23, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- “Dark Fried Tobacco,”, November 6, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Letter from Donald Davidson Regarding Potential Vanderbilt Authors, September 11, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Transcript of Oral Story of Dorothy Boykin, n. d. (Box 1, Folder 21)